

# **SUNIL THAKUR**

Web/Graphic Designer

#### **ABOUT**

BSC CSIT graduate, design enthusiast, and coding expert. I excel in crafting captivating graphics, seamless video edits, and compelling social media content. Known for achieving excellence through simplicity and efficiency, I bring a unique blend of technical and creative expertise to every project.

### **CONTACT**

- ① +977 9808976524
- sunilshady12@gmail.com
- Lalitpur, Nepal
- www.linkedin.com/in/im-sunilthakur/
- www.github.com/sunilthakur-np/

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

- Graphic Design Photoshop / Illustrator
- Video Editing Filmora, Movavi
- UI/UX Design / Figma
- MS Office Word, Power Point, Excel
- Digital Marketing Basics
- Webpage Design ReactJS, Tailwind CSS
- Basic C programs VS Code, Dev-C++

# OTHER INTERESTS

- Photography
- Table tennis
- Writing tech-blogs
- Learning new technologies

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

#### COMPUTER ASSISTANT / INSTRUCTOR (Aug 2023 - present)

Shree Bhimsen Secondary School, Bhotekoshi-05; Sindhupalchowk, Nepal

- Instructed computer basics, design & programming concepts to primary and secondary level students
- Designed event banners, certificates, social media / festival posts, letter head, engaging educational content / slides / videos etc.
- Prepared official documents, notices & teaching materials
- Conducted workshops on coding, designing using (c, html, CSS, photoshop, MS office, online Al tools etc.)

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER (Oct 2022 - Aug 2023)**

TechAxis Pvt. Ltd & JobAxle Pvt Ltd; Lalitpur, Nepal

- Created social media posts for Facebook, YouTube, LinkedIn, and Instagram
- Designed and produced print materials like sign boards, banner, flex board, ID card
  etc. including professional presentation slides/pdf, syllabus, documents and proposals
  visiting card, brochure, pen/spiral book covers and leaflets etc. for workshops and
  promotional ad campaigns
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to understand project objectives and target audience.
- Conducted user research and gathered feedback to inform design decisions.
- Additionally, I have experience in UI/UX design for in-house projects, where I translated conceptual ideas into visually appealing designs that effectively communicated the desired user experience.

For Reference: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/jobaxle/">https://www.facebook.com/techaxis.np/</a>

#### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP (Apr 2022 - Aug 2022)

Webpal Pvt Ltd; Lalitpur, Nepal

- Re-designed office's website using react js https://webpal.com.np/
- Designed logo for a news portal site <a href="https://punjibad.com/">https://punjibad.com/</a>
- Make page responsive <a href="https://onlinepasale.webpal.biz/">https://onlinepasale.webpal.biz/</a>

## WEB DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP (Mar 2022 - Apr 2022)

- Learned to design basic landing pages using HTML & CSS
- Designed a banner using Canva
- JS and PHP basic CRUD operations

#### OTHER PROJECTS:

- Final Year College Project Automatic News Summarization using HTML & CSS for frontend and Django for backend
- Personal Projects:
  - Personal portfolio website using HTML, CSS and JS. Link: https://sunilthakur-np.github.io/portfolio/
  - Editing videos/thumbnails for YouTube. Link: https://www.youtube.com/c/RapLyricsNepal
  - Figma website design.
  - Link: https://www.figma.com/@sunilthakur
  - Anil Furniture Udhyog (Social media posts, ads, banner etc)

#### **EDUCATION:**

**BSC CSIT** (2021), Kathford Int'l College of Engineering and Management +2 SCIENCE (2015), Omega Int'l College SLC (2013), AVM Higher Secondary School

# **TRAINING/COURSES:**

- Graphics & Webpage Designing from Precise Computers
- Flutter App Development course conducted by Kathford college
- Advanced PHP Course conducted by Kathford college
- 3-month Graphic Design at TechAxis Pvt Ltd